KAPIL PUNETHA

SEO SPECIALIST | CONTENT MARKETING | TECHNICAL SEO | KEYWORD STRATEGY

SUMMARY

SEO Analyst with over 4 years of experience in developing and executing effective SEO strategies to increase organic traffic, improve search engine rankings, and enhance online visibility. Skilled in comprehensive keyword research, on-page, technical SEO, content optimization, and backlink acquisition. Proficient with industry-leading SEO tools including Google Analytics, Google Search Console, SEMrush, and Ahrefs.

EXPERIENCE

SEO Analyst & Content Marketing Specialist

Elearning Platform B2b SaaS/ B2c.

- Increased organic website traffic by 40% in 6 months through comprehensive keyword strategies and technical SEO improvements.
- Conducted in-depth site audits, resolving over 50 technical issues to enhance crawl ability and site health.
- Developed and executed backlink acquisition campaigns, resulting in 100+ high-quality links and improved domain authority.
- Used SEMrush and Google Analytics to track KPIs, identify growth opportunities, and report results to the team.
- Worked on B2b SAAS Product Page Optimization.
- · Content Optimization.
- · Community Blog Posting.
- Conducted keyword research and developed comprehensive keyword strategies for website.

SEO Team Member

K12 Techno Services Pvt. Ltd.

d 08/2021 - 01/2022

Bengaluru

Education Service Provider

- · Backlinks and Guest Post Creation.
- Increased readership by consistent content posting on Medium.
- Content Optimization For SEO.
- Off page Activity.

Social Media Strategist

EdIndia Foundation

Non-profit organization based on education and career

- Improved social media engagement by {15%} through strategic optimization
- Increased viewership by {20%} through optimizing {50} YouTube videos using analytics tools.
- Data Entry.
- · Social media optimization.

Search Engine Optimization Executive

Brand Monkey

A digital marketing agency aimed at boosting client web presence.

- Managed on-page and off-page SEO activities to improve website rankings.
- Developed and implemented SEO strategies to enhance website visibility.
- Blog Post and optimization.
- Content Creation.
- · WordPress Page Optimization.
- Achieved 30% reduction in bounce rates by enhancing on-page SEO and improving user experience.

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

Boosted Organic Traffic

Increased web traffic by 40% through SEO in six months.



Improved Site Health

Resolved 50 technical SEO issues, enhancing site health by 25%.



Backlink Acquisition Success

Secured 50+ high-quality backlinks, enhancing domain authority by 10%.



Enhanced KPI Tracking

Tracked KPIs with SEMrush, identified 25% growth opportunities.



Social Media Enhancement

Improved community engagement by 20% through targeted content in medium.

CERTIFICATION

Certified Digital Marketing Master Course

Digital Vidya

The Fundamentals Of Digital Marketing

Google

Social Media Certified

HubSpot

Google Analytics individual

Google

Google Ads search certification

Facebook Marketing Certified

Facebook

STRENGTHS



Traffic enhancement skills

Proven ability to increase organic traffic and engagement.



Keyword strategy development

Expertise in developing and implementing keyword strategies.



Technical SEO proficiency

Skilled in conducting and resolving technical site audits.

EXPERIENCE

Search Engine Optimization Intern

Indietap

= 09/2020 - 12/2020

New Delhi, India

Elearning Platform

- Executed on-page SEO, optimizing keywords and content.
- Page Optimization By Updating meta, headers, schema and keywords implementation.

Website Designer

GST Support Services

A support center providing GST-related services

- Designed and developed WordPress websites for clients.
- Managed WordPress sites with {15} essential plugins, enhancing platform

Volunteer

NASSCOM Foundation

ii 08/2019 - 12/2019 **○** Noida, India

An organization that fosters growth in the tech sector through social responsibility.

- Increased social media engagement by {15%} through crafting and scheduling {80} targeted posts monthly.
- Developed and executed social media marketing campaigns to enhance brand
- · Social Media Post Creation For Engagement.

Social Media Marketing Intern

Hamari Pahchan - NGO

An NGO focused on community development

- Increased brand awareness by {25%} through a social media marketing campaign across {5} platforms.
- Increased brand awareness by {30%} by creating {50} targeted social media posts.

EDUCATION

Master's degree, Education

kumaun university

= 01/2016 - 12/2018

SKILLS

Ahrefs	Google Analytics		Google	Search Cons		
Search Console		SEMrush	SEO	O on-page off		page
content optimization conte			tent strate	ent strategy WordP		Chatgpt
Perplexity B2B Page Optimization						

STRENGTHS



Data-driven analysis skills

Track and analyze KPIs to enhance performance.



SEO Audit Proficiency

Experienced in conducting successful SEO



Analytics Tool Proficiency

Proficient in using SEMrush and Google Analytics.